# 大家好 你看 今天天氣比較好
Hi everyone! Look! The weather is better today.
# 把那小狗捉 捉下來 給他們玩一下
I bring, I bring the puppies down here, to let them have some fun here.
# 肥不肥
Isn't he fat?
# 像條豬一樣
Just like a pig
# 好胖啊
He's really fat.
# 現在可以下來走路啦
Now they can walk around down here.
# 狗狗狗狗狗狗狗
Puppies, puppies, puppies!
# 就你不聽話 叫得最大聲
You're the naughty boy, yelping the loudest.
# 誒呀 你想親我
Eya! You wanna kiss me?
# 走開
Go 'way!
# 抓一下 (註︰沒有一個不太突冗的翻譯，所以譯作「Come」算了)
Come!
# 狗 公狗 (註︰對狗的翻譯盡量人性點，避免外國聖母胡亂舉報)
Puppy! He's a boy.
# 你看
Look!
# 不怎麼可愛啦
He's not that cute anymore.
# 吃奶的時候好可愛呀 (註︰小狗未斷奶，所以可應該是指正在吃奶的樣子很可愛之類吧)
You looked so cute when you were sucking milk.
# 長大了就不可愛了你
Um, but not so when you grow up.
# 雙下巴
Double chin
# 一身肥膘 啊
The whole body is covered with fat, ah!
# 這一條
This one
# 這也是公的 這條
This is also a boy, this one.
# 小黑 這是你弟弟喲
Blacky! This is your little brother, you know?
# 不可以咬它啦
Don't bite him!
# 啊 這條叫得那麼大聲幹嘛
Ah! Why is this one yelping so loudly?
# 這條最胖 哈哈哈
This is the fattest, ha ha ha!
# 這個嘴巴好像不一樣啊 這個
His mouth seems to be a bit different, here.
# 長一點
It's a bit longer.
# 好胖呀
He's really fat.
# 還有一條
One more
# 這裡
Here
# 躲在這裡
He's hiding here.
# 吃奶吃
Having milk,
# 吃奶吃多啦 想吃點那個
having too much milk, they now want some, you know,
# 想吃點肉
they want some meat.
# 哈哈哈 在干嘛 咕咕咕咕的叫
Ha ha ha! What does he want? He's yelping like "goo goo goo goo".
# 你是怎麼啦
What happened to you?
# 你看 爪子好利呀
Look! His claws are really sharp!
# 快點 去吃東西
Come on! Get something to eat!
# 今天剛把它抓下來
I've just taken them down here today.
# 可能還有點一適應
Perhaps they still feel a bit unfamiliar.
# 適應了它就到 到處走啦
They would run around once they get used to the place.
# 以後就放下來養啦
Then they can simply be kept down here,
# 不到 不放上面去啦
in, instead of leaving them upstairs.
# 小狗
Puppy!
# 好好摸哇 它的毛
His hair feels so comfortable.
# 它的腳趾好像有點白白的
His toes seem to be a bit white.
# 老媽來啦
Mom is here.
# 快吃奶
Go suck some milk.
# 吃飽來
He's already full.
# 你看 這個一個月比這個幾個月的
Look! These one-month-old puppies are even heavier than,
# 比它還重哦
these several-month-old puppies.
# 一個月長了四于斤哦 這個五斤多哇 這小狗
They weigh more than 2 kg in just a month. This puppy is almost 3 kg.
# 這個也才六七斤
But this one is just a bit more than 3 kg.
# 長了四個月
But it's already four months old.